welcome back to another audacity
欢迎回到另一个大胆的地方
tutorial in this video I'll show you how
教程在本视频中 我将向您展示如何
to increase or decrease the volume of a
若要增加或减小
imported music file or sound file or of
导入的音乐文件或声音文件或
a file that you've recorded as an audio
已录制为音频的文件
that you've captured or recorded
你捕捉或记录的
yourself so to get started I'm just
你自己开始吧 我只是
going to drag and drop in an actual
将拖放到实际的
audio file we'll do this one of this
音频文件 我们来做这件事
jazz guitar just left-click and drag it
爵士吉他只需左键点击并拖动即可
in and then we see the audio file here
然后我们在这里看到音频文件
if we click we can play and listen to
如果我们点击 我们就可以播放和收听
what it sounds like and audio add so if
它听起来是什么样子 加上音频 如果
we want to increase the the volume of
我们想增加……的产量
this we've learned in the past we can
这是我们在过去学到的 我们可以
just increase the gain over here and
只需在这里增加收益 然后
this will actually affect the final
这实际上会影响到期末考试
output we can also just turn like the
输出 我们也可以像
volume up on our computer which is what
在我们的电脑上调大音量是什么
this knob up here is doing if we change
如果我们改变 这里的这个旋钮就会起作用
it up here it changes just the output
它在这里 它只改变输出
volume of our computer so that's
我们计算机的体积 所以这是
actually not that's gonna help us hear
实际上不是 这会帮助我们听到
it better but just know that's not going
最好是这样 但你要知道这是不可能的
to change the final output of this file
更改此文件的最终输出
and also when we change over here we see
此外 当我们在这里换乘时 我们看到
the wave doesn't change at all
波浪一点都不变
so if we want to change the way the wave
因此 如果我们想要改变波浪的方式
looks like actually amplify the the wave
看起来真的放大了电波
what we need to do is go up to effects
我们需要做的是提高效果
and go to amplify and when we just do it
然后去放大 当我们这么做的时候
just like this it's not gonna let us do
就像这样 它不会让我们做
anything because it says you have no
任何事情 因为它说你没有
selection so by default audacity doesn't
选择 因此默认情况下 Audity不会
assume that we want to just amplify the
假设我们只想放大
entire audio file it wants us to choose
它想让我们选择整个音频文件
so we could say just amplify this
所以我们可以说 只是放大这个
portion if we left click and drag and
部分 如果我们左键单击并拖动
highlight we can highlight a certain
突出显示我们可以突出显示某一特定内容
part of it or we can press ctrl-a to
或者我们可以按ctrl-a组合键
select all another way to select all is
选择所有其他方式以选择全部为
to go up to select and click all so
要向上选择并单击All so 请执行以下操作
let's select all we can go select none
让我们选择我们能去的所有选项不选择
we can select by track we only have one
我们可以按曲目选择 我们只有一个
track right now but let's go select all
现在开始跟踪 但让我们选择全部
and now that everything selected we can
现在我们所能选择的一切
go back to effects and go to amplify and
返回到特效并放大和
now it brings up this window here so
现在它打开了这个窗口 所以
audio levels are measured in decibels
音频级别是以分贝为单位测量的
this DB and so this is this is gonna
这个数据库 所以这就是这个
amplify it by seven decibels right now
现在就放大7分贝
if we had this set to zero there'd be no
如果我们把这个设置为零 就不会有
amplification so the zero is kind of the
放大 所以零是一种
neutral point right now if I say okay
如果我说好的话现在就是中立点
nothing happens everything looks the
什么都没发生 一切看起来
same it's not any louder or any softer
同样 它不会更响亮 也不会更柔和
but control a to select everything again
但控制a再次选择所有内容
if we go to effects amplify and if we
如果我们去效果放大 如果我们
have it above zero it's going to amplify
如果它高于零 它就会放大
it make it louder if we have it below
如果我们把它放在下面 声音就会更大
zero in the negative it's going to make
负数为零 这将使
it softer quieter
它更柔和 更安静
so let's come up to list it was here by
所以让我们来列出它是在
default like I've said a seven basically
违约 就像我说的 基本上是7
it was I think to almost its height like
我想几乎到了它的高度 就像
the highest it could possibly amplify it
它可能放大它的最高值
until it starts clipping the audio
直到它开始剪辑音频
remember clipping is when the wave goes
记住 剪裁是当海浪离开的时候
above the very top above this 100% so if
在这个100%以上的最上面 所以如果
we go any high we can click OK now but
我们走到任何高度 我们现在都可以点击OK 但是
if we go any higher than this it's gonna
如果我们再走得更高 它就会
get grayed out and we can't click OK
显示为灰色 我们无法单击确定
unless we check this box here it says
除非我们勾选这个框 否则上面写着
allow clipping but so let's just come
允许剪裁 但我们还是来吧
down we'll come down to about maybe
我们可能会降到大概
right here and we'll click OK and then
就在这里 我们将单击确定 然后
we see our wave it gets larger and we
我们看到我们的波浪 它变得更大 我们
can actually play and it's a louder
可以真正地演奏 而且声音更大
volume now we can see up in our activity
现在我们可以在我们的活动中看到音量增加
up here that it's louder if we wanted to
在这里 如果我们想的话声音会更大
undo that and maybe we want to change it
撤销它 也许我们想要改变它
we used to control Z to undo or we can
我们过去常常控制Z来撤消 或者我们可以
use these undo and redo buttons up here
使用此处的撤消和重做按钮
let's select everything again and this
让我们再选择一次所有东西 然后这个
time let's try to make it softer so we
时间让我们试着让它变得更柔和
go to effects amplify and then we'll
转到效果放大 然后我们将
change it let's go down to maybe that
改变它 让我们继续下去 也许是这样
same extreme maybe I can negative 5 or 6
同样的极端 也许我可以负5或6
and we'll go okay so now it's kind of
我们会走得很好 所以现在有点像
much much more quiet and soft so this is
更安静 更柔和 所以这是
actually adjusting the way that's
实际上调整的方式是
actually modifying the actual sound the
实际上修改了实际的声音
wave that makes up the sound and either
构成声音的波 或者
making it louder or softer so that's a
让它变得更响亮或更柔和 所以这是一个
quick introduction and this is actually
简单介绍一下 这实际上是
the direction to using effects in
在中使用效果的方向
general so we'll do this the same way if
将军 如果我们用同样的方法来做
we want to apply you can read through
我们想申请你可以通读
some of the some of these other effects
其中的一些其他影响
and we'll be jumping through a lot of
我们将会跳过很多
them in the next tutorials but just
在接下来的教程中 但只是
remember you have to have everything
记住 你必须拥有一切
selected and I guess let's just try that
被选中 我想我们就试一试吧
for now if we want to have just this one
现在 如果我们只想要这一张
portion of the song
歌曲的一部分
this part right here if we want to make
这部分就在这里 如果我们想要
just this loud we can just have this
就这么大声 我们就可以拥有这个
selected like we do and then go to
像我们一样选择 然后转到
effects amplify and then we can make it
效果会放大 然后我们就能做到
loud and that's actually let's bring it
大声地说 那就是让我们带来它
clear up here and let's go allow
把这里清理干净 我们去让
clipping so this is going to Phi this
剪裁 所以这将是Phi这
incredibly loud so loud that it actually
令人难以置信的声音如此之大以至于它实际上
comes above the total at the top of this
位于此顶部的总和之上
like the of the part that we can see so
就像我们可以看到的那部分
we go okay and now look how that's just
我们走得很好 现在看看这是怎么回事
crazy that's gonna be loud and ugly I'll
疯狂 这将是响亮和丑陋的 我会
do the anti so it's not too out for us
做反击 这样我们就不会太出局了
so you can see it's distorted it's
所以你可以看到它被扭曲了
clipped that's louder than we would want
这比我们想要的要大得多
and something I want to show if we were
还有一些我想展示的东西 如果我们是
to highlight this now and we're like oh
现在强调这一点 我们就像哦
it's the if we want to undo that change
这是如果我们想要撤销这一变化
we should click undo but if we want to
我们应该单击撤消 但如果我们想要
do it the wrong way we go back to
以错误的方式去做 我们会回到
amplify and be like let's take it back
放大 就像让我们把它带回去
down to try and correct it but now look
向下试着纠正它 但现在看看
what happens if we do that and then
如果我们这么做了 然后
we're like oh that's too small and then
我们就像 哦 那太小了 然后
we go to effect amplify again to try and
我们再去放大效果试一试
change it what we're gonna see is if we
改变它 我们将看到的是 如果我们
look at this wave now look how look at
现在看看这个浪 看看怎么看
it it's like all just flat and ugly so
这一切就像是平淡而丑陋的
if we zoom in here here we can just
如果我们放大这里 我们可以
select it and I click this button here
选中它 然后我点击此处的按钮
so it seems into the total selection so
所以它似乎进入了总的选择所以
it's just look it's completely square
只是看起来它完全是正方形的
now it's a lot different than it was
现在和以前有很大的不同
before because we've messed around with
以前是因为我们在一起
it and we amplified it and then put it
我们放大了它 然后把它
down so if ever you wanted to make
所以如果你想做的话
changes the way to to reverse an
将方式更改为反转
amplification is just to do the undo not
放大只是为了做不做的事
to come back in here and lower the level
回到这里降低水平
or raise the level after the fact does
或者在事实发生后提高水平
that make sense so if I want to get this
这是有道理的所以如果我想得到这个
back to how it was originally I just
回到原来的样子
push back and back and back until we get
推啊推啊推直到我们
back to the original hopefully found
回到原来的希望
this video informative that's using
这段视频内容丰富
amplification go ahead and play with
放大继续玩
that we can also use it on our own
我们也可以自己使用它
recorded audio and yeah that's basically
录制的音频 是的
using the amplification effect go ahead
使用放大效果继续
and LIKE comment subscribe and I'll see
和喜欢评论订阅 我会看到
you in the next video
你在下一个视频